# Carl McGee

Minnetonka, Minnesota

**Phone**: 952-693-8217l Email: Carl.Jack.McGee@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/carl-mcgee-3b9648a0/

**Github**: <a href="https://github.com/CarlJMcGee">https://github.com/CarlJMcGee</a>

Portfolio: https://carljmcgee.github.io/carls-react-portfolio/

# Summary

Junior full stack developer with a background in public health. Experienced in mobile-first, user-friendly web applications. Experienced using creative problem solving and communicating with peers to diagnose and fix issues as they arise. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from the University of Minnesota.

# Technical Skills.

Software: VS Code, TRPC, NextAuth, Postman, GraphQL Playground, Browser Developer Tools

Websites: Github, Gitlab, Heroku, Vercel, Planetscale, MongoAtlas

Tech Stacks: T3 Stack, MERN

CSS-in-JS: Bootstrap, Bulma, Tailwind

Software Languages: HTML 5, CSS, Java/Type Script, JQuery, React, Next.js, Prisma, SQL

# Relevant Experience

#### Movie Night Randomizer |

February 2022 - August 2022

https://github.com/CarlJMcGee/movie-picker |

https://shit-screen-movie-picker.vercel.app/

**Description:** A site for organizing my movies for my friends to see what I have available and add movies to a wish list for me

to find and purchase later.

My Contribution: The project was created and is maintained by myself.

Tools Used: Made using the T3 Stack (Typescript, Tailwind, TRPC, Prisma, Next.js, NextAuth),

and Bootstrap React

### Neighborhood chat/social site |

February 2022 - August 2022

https://github.com/CarlJMcGee/Geo-Chat\_Neighborhood-group-chat | https://geo-chatneighborhood-group-chat-production.up.railway.app/

Description: A site for locals to connect and socialize online with the people living around them. Sign up with your city

name and be automatically added to your neighborhood's homepage

My Contribution: Worked on the database design and implementation as well as the API endpoints

Tools Used: Made using Vanilla Javascript, Express, and Handlebars.

## Avatar Legends TTRPG online character sheet

February 2022 - August 2022

https://github.com/CarlJMcGee/Avatar-Legends-character-sheet |

https://avatar-legends-character-sheet-production.up.railway.app/

**Description:** An unofficial online character sheet alternative for the Avatar the Last Airbender tabletop RPG by Magpie Games.

**My Contribution:** The project was designed and created by myself **Tools Used:** Made using Vanilla Javascript, Express, and Handlebars.

### **Automation Specialist**

February 2021 - Present

# **Memorial Blood Center**

St. Paul. Minnesota

- Perform physical examinations of donor vitals and reviewing medical history to determine fitness to donate
- Quickly and carefully prepare and label donation bags and equipment
- Set up automated donations machines and performing venipunctures for Whole Blood, Double Red Cell, and Plasma donations using aseptic technique
- Respond to donor adverse reactions during or after the donation procedure
- Create positive donor experiences through good customer service and a comfortable environment to promote repeat donations

#### Lead Phlebotomist/ Lead Donor Center Technician/Designated Trainer

September 2017 - January 2021

### **Grifols Talecris Plasma Resources**

West St. Paul, Minnesota

- Organized and moved staff to critical areas as needed
- Ensured staff were getting breaks and advocating employee issues to management
- Trained new and cross-training employees and helped them perform at expected levels
- Registered applicant donors into the system and reviewed them for deferrable items
- Set up apheresis machines with disposable softgoods and prepared donors for venipuncture and performed venipunctures for plasma donation
- Monitoring donor condition during the donation process and responding to donor safety issues and emergencies

#### **End-User Technology Associate**

January 2017 - August 2017

## **Ameriprise Financial**

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Reviewed and ensured security compliance in Microsoft Enterprise products
- Recorded software changes to the digital infrastructure
- Assisted in the development and deployment of Microsoft Outlook desktop and mobile in the Microsoft Business 365
  Suite
- Reviewed trends in service desk requests for Microsoft Outlook desktop and mobile
- Tested new features and security updates to Outlook prior to End-User deployment
- Assisted End-Users with new features and changes

# Education

Certificate: University of Minnesota | Minneapolis, Minnesota

February 2022 - August 2022

An intensive 6 month program focused on full stack web development in Javascript. The course covered basic front-end HTML 5, CSS, and Javascript all the way through full stack single page React apps with the MERN stack.